# 1

# Arnab Majumdar

Gallup Strengths: Futuristic, Ideation, Command, Intellection, Input

VendMyT.com. arnab@VendMyT.com +1-401-871-8377 github.com/arnab156 linkedin.com/in/arnab156

"Arnab is a full stack web development student who is detail-oriented, fast-paced, and creative. In his previous experiences, he has excelled in problem-solving, multi-tasking, and more importantly, learned valuable professional and life lessons. Arnab is a self-starter, solution-oriented and believes in continuous development. He is interested in entry-level front-end development or full-stack development positions in organizations that are future-oriented and are global in perspective such as yours!"

**TECHNICAL SKILLS:** HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, jQuery, Bootstrap, Materialize, Express.js, React.js, Node.js, Database Theory, MongoDB, MySQL, Firebase, Sequelizejs, Mongoose, Command Line, Git, Trello, Microsoft Office, Abode Photoshop & Illustrator. Basic knowledge of Python.

STRENGTHS: Quick Learner, Team Player, Solution Oriented, Creative, Empathetic Decision Maker

#### **EDUCATION**

Northwestern University, Chicago, IL

May -Nov 2018

Northwestern Boot Camp – Full Stack Web Development

Project 1: Adam Front Desk - adamfrontdesk.herokuapp.com/

- O **Description**: a front-desk application that enables efficient communication between customers, front-desk staff, and service providers ideal for offices, academia, salons, restaurants, etc.
- o **Technologies used**: Passport Authentication, JavaScript, Express, Sequelizejs, MySQL.
- o GitHub: https://github.com/arnab156/Project-2

Project 2: **Book Buzz -** bookbuzz25.herokuapp.com

- O **Description:** BookBuzz is an application created for users to find new books to read, save for later, create book clubs and join clubs based on their reading interests.
- o Technologies used: MERN Stack Mongodb, Express, React, Node, Google API
- o GitHub: https://github.com/Bookbuzz/Bookbuzz.git

Project 3: Gym Rat - arnab156.github.io/gymrat/

- O Description: a one stop shop for all of your gym needs and motivates the users to live a healthy lifestyle.
- o **Technologies used:** Google (Maps &\* YouTube API, iTunes API, Food2Fork API, Weather Map API, Materialize, JavaScript, Firebase.
- o GitHub: <a href="https://github.com/arnab156/gymRat">https://github.com/arnab156/gymRat</a>

# University of Rhode Island, Kingston, RI

May 2012

Master of Science in Textiles, Fashion Merchandising & Design

### National Institute of Fashion Technology, Bangalore, India

May 2008

Bachelor of Apparel Manufacturing and Information Technology

• Commercially Most Viable Project Award: "Size standardization for kids-wear in India"

# **EXPERIENCE**

### Northwestern University, Chicago, IL

Full-time Coding Development - Teaching Assistant

Dec 2018 - Present

- Mentoring, and assisting students for successful completion of the course.
- Grading using rubrics and assisting instructors in smooth functioning of the class.

# VendMyT, LLC, Chicago, IL

Co-Founder Jan 2017 - Present

- Conceptualized and created a new innovative activewear brand from scratch.
- Use creative software to make line sheets, tech packs and collaterals.
- Developed and analyzed fit of the product and create updated graded specification for each product.

# 2

# Arnab Majumdar

Gallup Strengths: Futuristic, Ideation, Command, Intellection, Input

VendMyT.com. arnab@VendMyT.com +1-401-871-8377 github.com/arnab156 linkedin.com/in/arnab156

- Source, manage, and develop activewear vendors internationally.
- Manage customer returns and complaints for continuous product improvement.
- Create Pop-Up shops and other sales related activities.

# Fashion Marketing Management, Northwood University, Midland, MI

Department Chair and Assistant Professor,

Aug 2017 - Aug 2018

- Create, instruct, communicate and grade using Learning Management Systems.
- Use creative software, MS Excel, and online tools to create materials targeted towards today's students.
- Organize industry visits such as Magic trade show, Global Shop, etc.

# Fashion Studies, Columbia College Chicago, Chicago, IL

Assistant Professor, Fashion Business & International Student Mentor

Aug 2013 – May 2017

- Conceptualized, and created innovative and global projects such as Eye on India Sew Sari project, AT&T Samsung design projects that were showcased in Willis Tower, Bridgeport Art Center, etc.
- Lead Fashion Studies in organizational committees such as Faculty Senate, Academic Affairs, and Assessment.

# Family and Consumer Science Department - Pittsburg State University, Pittsburg, KS

Instructor, Fashion Merchandising

Aug 2012 – May 2013

• Integrated MS Excel in instruction for Fashion Merchandising Buying for OTB, 6 month merchandise plan, Margin, Assortment plan, Mark up, Mark down calculations, etc.

# Ocean State Job Lot, North Kingston, RI

Intern, Distribution and Logistic

Jun-Aug 2011

• Developed consolidated databases of stores, drivers, capacity & time schedules that saved time in D&L

### The University of Rhode Island, Kingston, RI

Teaching Assistant & Textile Testing Technician.

Aug 2010 – May 2012

- Guide, prepare and demonstrate lab techniques and procedures for undergraduate students
- Analyze fabric and conduct various AATCC and ASTM tests for industrial clients

### Reliance Trends Limited, Bangalore, India

Assistant Marketing Manager, Events, Promotions & Communication

Apr 2007 - Jun 2010

- Managed quarterly marketing spends by apportioning and auditing the budget for apparel category
- Analyzed and tracked sales data by measuring key parameters such as Average Ticket Values, Conversions, Basket Size, etc. using DSS for tracking and projection
- Planned and launched 2 private labels and 3 new stores openings
- Collaborated with the brand managers and creative agencies for seasonal marketing campaigns

### Other Internships:

<u>PR Internship</u> – StyleWeek LLC, Providence; <u>Apparel Production Internship</u> – WonderBlues Ltd. India; <u>Textile Internship</u> – Siyarams Silk Mills, Mumbai; <u>Textile Internship</u> – Indira Gandhi Sahkari Soot, India.

COMMUNITY: Volunteer Docent - Lincoln Park Conservatory

**LANGUAGE:** Hindi, Bengali, English